A Guide to the Code of Virginia Recodification records of the Virginia Code Commission, 1904-2009
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Code of Virginia Recodification records of the Virginia Code Commission, 1904-2009
The Library of Virginia
23346, 37986, 41443, 50534, 51825, 53906
64.05 cu. ft. (66 boxes)
Virginia Code Commission
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 4 May 1949 by the Division of Legislative Services, Virginia Code Commission, General Assembly Building, 2nd Floor, Richmond, VA 23219 [Acc. 23346].
Transferred on 12 February 2001 by the Division of Legislative Services, Virginia Code Commission, General Assembly Building, 2nd Floor, Richmond, VA 23219 [Acc. 37986].
Transferred on an unknown date by the Division of Legislative Services, Virginia Code Commission, General Assembly Building, 2nd Floor, Richmond, VA 23219 [Acc. 41443].
Transferred on 16 July 2012 by the Division of Legislative Services, Virginia Code Commission, General Assembly Building, 2nd Floor, Richmond, VA 23219 [Acc. 50534].
Transferred on 14 June 2016 by the Division of Legislative Services, Virginia Code Commission, General Assembly Building, 2nd Floor, Richmond, VA 23219 [Acc. 51825].
Transferred on 17 May 2023 by the Division of Legislative Services, Virginia Code Commission, General Assembly Building, 2nd Floor, Richmond, VA 23219 [Acc. 53906].
Biographical Information
The Commission on Code Recodification was created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 30, 1946. Its principal duty was to make a complete recodification of the statute laws of the state of a general nature. This task was completed two years later, and the new code was approved by the General Assembly on March 30, 1948.
An act passed by the General Assembly on March 16, 1948, made the commission a permanent agency of the legislative branch of government and changed the name of the commission to the Virginia Code Commission. The commission supervises the codification of the statutes after each General Assembly session and revises and recodifies portions of the Code of Virginia as needed.
In 1992 the Commission was charged with the responsibility of creating Virginia's first administrative code of regulations by compiling and codifying all of the administrative regulations of state agencies. The Commission also oversees the bi-weekly publication of The Virginia Register of Regulations, which is used by state agencies during the adoption of new regulations to be included in the Administrative Process Act.
Please note that the materials related to the 1904 revision of the Code of Virginia were created prior to the creation of the Virginia Code Commission in 1946. These materials are of similar nature to those of the 1948 records, and were grouped together for cataloging purposes.
Scope and Content
Records, 1904-2009, documenting all drafts and final revisions, supporting correspondence and supplemental information regarding the recodification of the Code of Virginia. Includes working papers, notes, worksheets and proofs. The earlier records, 1904 and 1948, consist of printed copies of sections of the Code glued onto paper or in scrapbooks with notes, changes to the wording, and code citations marked. Also included are correspondence and copies of pre-1948 laws for various state agencies.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1948-1953 [Acc. 23346]
Series II: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1974-1997 [Acc. 37986]
Series III: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1904 [Acc. 41443]
Series IV: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1982-2004 [Acc. 50534]
Series V: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 2007-2009 [Acc. 51825]
Series VI: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1998-2007 [Acc. 53906].
Contents List
- Series I: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1948-1953 [Acc. 23346]., Extent: 16 cu. ft. (15 boxes). (Box 1-15)
  - Work sheets of the Virginia Code Commission on the 1948 revision of code, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
  - Report of the Commission on the Code Recodification, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Table of comparative sections, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Table of Acts of 1947, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Title 1: General Provisions, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Title 2: Administration of the Government, Generally, Chapters 1-16, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Title 3: Agriculture, Horticulture, Food, and other Commodities, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 4-8)
  - Title 4: Alcoholic Beverages and Industrial Alcohol, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Title 5: Aviation, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Title 6: Banking and Finance, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11-15)
  - Title 7: Boundaries, Jurisdiction, and Emblems of the Commonwealth, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Title 8: Civil Remedies and Procedures; Evidence, Generally, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Title 9: Commissions, Boards, and Institutions, Generally, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Title 10: Conservation, Generally, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Title 11: Contracts, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Title 12: Corporation Commission, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Title 13: Corporations, Generally, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
  - Title 14: Costs, Fees, Salaries, and Allowances, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 14-16)
  - Title 15: Counties, Cities, and Towns, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
  - Title 16: Courts Not of Record, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Title 17: Courts of Record, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
  - Title 18: Crimes and Offenses, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 12-15)
  - Title 19: Criminal Procedures, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 16-18)
  - Title 20: Domestic Relations, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Title 21: Drainage, Soil Conservation, and Public Facilities Districts, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 2-5)
  - Title 22: Education, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
  - Title 23: Educational Institutions, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 10-12)
  - Title 24: Elections, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 13-17)
  - Title 25: Eminent Domain, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
  - Title 26: Fiduciaries, Generally, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Title 27: Fire Protection, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Title 28: Fish, Oysters, and Shellfish, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
  - Title 29: Game and Inland Fisheries and Dogs, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Title 30: General Assembly, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Title 31: Guardian and Ward, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Title 32: Health, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 10-13)
  - Title 33: Highways, Bridges, and Ferries, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 14-17)
  - Title 34: Homestead and Other Exemptions, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Title 35: Hotels and Camps, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Title 36: Housing, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Title 37: Insane, Epileptic, Feeble-Minded, and Inebriate Persons, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
  - Title 38: Insurance, 1948 (Box 6A, Folder 1-5)
  - Title 39: Justices of the Peace, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Title 40: Labor and Employment, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Title 41: Land Office, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Title 42: Libraries, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Title 43: Mechanics' and Other Liens, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Title 44: Military and War Emergency Laws, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - Title 45: Mines and Mining, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Title 46: Motor Vehicles, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 9-14)
  - Title 47: Notaries and Out of State Commissioners, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Title 48: Nuisances, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Title 49: Oaths, Affirmations, and Bonds, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Title 50: Partnerships, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Title 51: Pensions and Retirement, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
  - Title 52: Police (State), 1948 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Title 53: Prisons and Other Methods of Correction, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 22-25)
  - Title 54: Professions and Occupations, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 1-8)
  - Title 55: Property and Conveyances, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
  - Title 56: Public Service Companies, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 12-16)
  - Title 57: Religious and Charitable Matters; Cemeteries, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Title 58: Taxation, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 18-20)
  - Title 58: Taxation, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 1-8)
  - Title 59: Trade and Commerce, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
  - Title 60: Unemployment Compensation, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Title 61: Warehouses, Cold Storage, and Refrigerator Locker Plants, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - Title 62: Waters of the State, Ports and Harbors, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 15-16)
  - Title 63: Welfare, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 17-20)
  - Title 64: Wills and Decedents Estates, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Title 65: Workmen's Compensation, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 1: General Provisions, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 2: Administration of the Government, Generally, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 3: Agriculture, Horticulture, and Food, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 4: Alcoholic Beverages and Industrial Alcohol, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 5: Aviation, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 6: Banking and Finance, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 7: Boundaries, Jurisdiction, and Emblems of the Commonwealth, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 8: Civil Remedies and Procedure; Evidence, Generally, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 9: Commissions, Boards, and Institutions, Generally, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 10: Conservation, Generally, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 11: Contracts, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 12: Corporation Commission, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 13: Corporations, Generally, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 14: Costs, Fees, Salaries, and Allowances, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 15: Counties, Cities, and Towns, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 16: Courts Not of Record, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 17: Courts of Record, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 18: Crimes and Offenses, Generally, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 19: Criminal Procedures, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 20: Domestic Relations, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 21: Drainage, Soil Conservation, Sanitary, and Other Public Facilities Districts, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 22: Education, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 23: Educational Institutions, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 24: Elections, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 25: Eminent Domain, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 26: Fiduciaries, Generally, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 27: Fire Protection, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 28: Fish, Oysters, and Shellfish, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 29: Game and Inland Fisheries and Dogs, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 30: General Assembly, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 31: Guardian and Ward, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 32: Health, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 33: Highways, Bridges, and Ferries, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 34: Homestead and Other Exemptions, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 35: Hotels and Camps, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 36: Housing, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 37: Insane, Epileptic, Feeble-Minded, and Inebriate Persons, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 38: Insurance, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 39: Justices of the Peace, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 40: Labor and Employment, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 41: Land Office, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 42: Libraries, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 43: Mechanics and Certain Other Liens, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 44: Military and War Emergency Laws, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 45: Mines and Mining, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 46: Motor Vehicles, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 47: Notaries and Out-of-State Commissioners, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 48: Nuisances, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 49: Oaths, Affirmations, and Bonds, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 50: Partnerships, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 51: Pensions and Retirements, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 52: Police, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 53: Prisons and Other Methods of Correction, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 54: Professions and Occupations, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 55: Property and Conveyances, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 56: Public Service Companies, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 57: Religious and Charitable Matters; Cemeteries, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 58: Taxation, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 59: Trade and Commerce, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 60: Unemployment Compensation, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 61: Warehouses, Cold Storage, and Refrigerated Locker Plants, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 62: Waters of the State, Ports, and Harbors, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 63: Welfare, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 64: Wills and Decedents' Estates, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Gallery Proofs, Title 65: Workmen's Compensation, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 2, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 3, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 6, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 8, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 13, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 14, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 15, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 16, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 17, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 18, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 19, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 21, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 22, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 23, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 24, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 25, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 26, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 27, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 28, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 29, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 31, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 32, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 33, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 37, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 38, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 40, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 41, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title- 42, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 43, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 44, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 46, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 51, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 53, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 54, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 55, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 56, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 58, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 59, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 63, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Discarded-Omitted Materials, Title 65, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Introduction, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 1-3, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 6-8, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 8-13, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 13-14, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 14-15, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 15-16, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 16-18, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 18-21, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 21-22, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 22-24, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume I, Page Proof, Titles 24-28, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Introduction, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 29-32, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 32-38, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 38-40, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 40-44, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 44-46, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 46-51, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 51-53, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Title 54, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 54-56, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Titles 56-58, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Title 58, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Title 58-60, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Title 60-63, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Title 63-65, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification and Proposed Code of Virginia, Volume II, Page Proof, Table of comparative sections, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Letter from E. Griffith Dodson to William J. Van Schreever, State Archivist, 1953 September 29 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Lists of laws received by the Code Commission from State Agencies, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Laws, Accountancy, State Board of, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Laws, Administrative Code of Virginia, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Laws, Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Laws, State Anatomical Board, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Laws, Alcoholic Beverage Acts, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Laws, Arts, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Laws, State Bar of Attorneys, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Laws, Auditor of Public Accounts, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Laws, Aviation and Aeronautics, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Laws, Banking, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Laws, Commission for the Blind, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Laws, Dept. of Budget, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Laws, Constitution of Virginia (1945), 1948 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Laws, State Board for Contractors, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Laws, Dept. of Corrections, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Laws, State Board of Dental Examiners, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Laws, State Board for Education, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 27-28)
  - Laws, Election laws, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Laws, Electric Cooperatives, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Laws, Forestry-Fisheries-Conservation, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Laws, Division of Grounds and Buildings, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Laws, Dept. of Health, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Laws, Insurance, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Laws, Labor and Mining, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Laws, Lobbyists, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Laws, Machine Gun Act, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Laws, Madison College, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Laws, Marriage and Maternity, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Laws, Motion Pictures, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Laws, Motor Vehicles, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Laws, Personnel Act, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Laws, Board of Pharmacy, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Laws, State Board of Planning, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Laws, Police (State), 1948 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Laws, Public Utilities, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Laws, Railroads and Transportation, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Laws, Real Estate, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Laws, Retirement Act, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Laws, Securities, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Laws, State Corporation Commission, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Laws, Statutory Research and Drafting Division, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Laws, Surplus Federal Property Commission, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Laws, Tax Code, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Laws, Trade Marks, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Laws, Unemployment, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Laws, Veterans, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Laws, Virginia Tech, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Laws, State Board of Welfare, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 28)
- Series II: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1974-1997 [Acc. 37986]., Extent: 34 cu. ft. (34 boxes). (Box 1-34)
  - Title 13.1: Stock Corporation Act, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1, 2, 6, 12)
  - Title 13.1: Stock Corporation Act and Code Commission meeting, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4, 7-10, 16, 19-21)